啊。
Ah.
来吧。
Come on.
看着我。
Look at me.
他去哪了?
Where'd he get to?
我不知道。
I don't know.
不!
No!
把绳子。
Get the rope.
我们的…向东，向印度领土进发。
We's... headin' east, towards indian territory.
他的情况很糟。
He's in a bad way.
关于这件事，你就想说这些吗?
Is that everything you have to say on the matter?
我发誓。我发誓!
I swear. i swear!
你知道吗?
You know what?
我相信你。
I believe you.
哇。达根。
Whoa. duggan.
哇。
Whoa.
地狱吗?
The hell?
你怎么知道这事会变成这样
How the hell you figure this wound up
在这片草原的中央吗?
Out here in the middle of these grassland?
这会很顺利的。
This will work out nice.
给我松绑。
Just cut me loose.
你再也见不到我了，真的。给我松绑。
You'll never see me again, honest. just cut me loose.
坐起来。
Sit on up.
你看，我本想把你放了，
Well, you see, i would cut you loose,
但这违背了我的正义感。
But that just violates my sense of what's right.
很难分辨一个男人是谁，是什么
it can be hard to tell who and what a man is,
他想让你相信他不是这样的
he's got a mind to convince you otherwise.
我的家人来自纽约，我出生的地方
my people were from new york, where i was born.
当我三岁的时候，
by the time i was three,
我们已经到达了堪萨斯州的coffeyville
we'd made it to coffeyville, kansas,
然后去亚利桑那，然后去新墨西哥
then down to arizona, then new mexico.
我在墨西哥待过一段时间
i was in mexico proper for a time.
我在许多行业都干过
i've tried my hand at many a vocation.
一些比其他的更边缘
some more marginal than others.
最后，我决定过农民的生活
finally, i settled on the life of a farmer.
我是什么。
which is what i am.
我们养了那头猪，
We got that hog, stock to feed,
还有一个地窖要填满。
And a root cellar to fill.
现在的拖拉机只需要四分之一的时间就能做到。
There's tractors can do this now in quarter the time.
是这样吗?
Is that right?
我想
And here i thought
你的骨子里就有农业，怀亚特。
Farming was in your bones, wyatt.
这对你来说是个好地方
This would be a good place for you
养活自己的家庭。
To raise a family of your own.
我知道你妈也会这么想。
I know your ma would have felt that way.
我不是她。
I ain't her.
或者他。
Or him.
房屋凭智慧建造，
By wisdom is a house built,
这都是借着理解建立起来的。
And through understanding is it established.
其屋因知识充满
Through knowledge are its rooms filled
拥有稀有而美丽的珍宝。
With rare and beautiful treasures.
踏上朝圣之路的人有福了。
And blessed are those hearts that are set on pilgrimage.
虽然我很想留下来…
Much as i'd like to stick around...
听你们互相引用经文…
Listen to y'all quote scripture at each other...
我要去猎鸟。
I'm goin' bird huntin'.
谢谢你的帮助，艾尔。
Thanks for the help, al.
来到这里对我有好处。
It does me good to be here.
让我觉得我和玛丽还在一起。
Makes me feel like i'm still connected to marie somehow.
帮你叔叔拿他的东西。
Give your uncle a hand with his things.
也就是说，如果你有足够的休息时间。
That is, if you've had sufficient respite.
谢谢你,儿子。
Thank you, son.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
我今天早上想去打猎
Yeah, i wanted to go huntin' this mornin',
但你爸爸说他需要帮助。
But your pa said he needed some help.
我很想哪天和你一起去。
Sure would like to go with you one of these days.
我觉得这样不太好。
I don't think that'd go over too well.
你爸是个好人，怀亚特。
Your pa's a good man, wyatt.
我不会让他娶我妹妹的
I wouldn't let him marry my sister
如果我不这么认为的话。
If i didn't think so.
很快，你就能
Soon enough, you'll be able to
你想去哪儿就去哪儿。
Do all the travelin' and shootin' you want to.
别为这事烦恼了。
Stop frettin' about it.
我们晚饭吃两份排骨，其余的用烟熏。
We'll take two chops for supper and smoke the rest.
我没时间渲染了。把它扔进围栏里。
I ain't got time to render this. throw it in the pen.
有时候你不觉得烦吗，他们吃自己的?
Don't it bother you sometimes, they eat their own?
对猪来说没什么区别。
Don't make no difference to a hog.
你为什么定居在这里?
Why'd you settle here?
那是什么意思?
What's that meant to mean?
为什么?为什么偏偏是领土呢?
Why? why the territory, of all places?
你可以提出要求，
You could stake a claim,
保管一年，它是你的。
Hang onto it for a year, it was yours.
当时看来是笔不错的交易。
Seemed like a pretty good deal at the time.
在枪声响起之前赶到的，你知道的。
Got here before the guns went off, you know that.
我还是不相信这是你想要的。
I still don't believe this is what you wanted.
拂晓就起床，喂牲口，收割庄稼。
Up at dawn, feedin' the stock, workin' the crops.
无论热或冷，下雨或晴天。
Hot or cold, rain or shine.
你会发现还有更糟糕的安排。
You'll discover there's worse arrangements.
爸爸?
Pa?
放松，姑娘，就这样。
Easy, gal, that's it.
我身边就有一匹母马吗
Had me a mare near just like this
当我比你大不了多少的时候
When i wasn't much older than you.
Lookie这里。
Lookie here.
你觉得发生了什么?某种抢劫?
What do you think happened? some kind of robbery?
——一个枪战吗?-闭嘴。
- a shootout? - shut your nonsense.
我最好去找那个骑手。
I'd best go look for the rider.
好，我去备马鞍。
Yeah, i'll go saddle up.
你去照看这匹马，待在屋里等我回来。
You tend to this horse and stay inside till i get back.
但是如果是麻烦呢，爸爸?我可以帮你。
But what if it's trouble, pa? i can help you.
继续。照我说的做。
Go on. do as i say.
你好。
Hello.
不。
Nope.
怀亚特!
Wyatt!
-他还活着吗?——几乎没有。
- is he alive? - barely.
他独自一人吗?
Was he alone?
没有，但我派出了十几个人在那里。
No, but i dispatched with a dozen others was there.
帮我个忙。
Give me a hand.
他的……他失血过多。
He's... he's lost a lot of blood.
他能活下来吗?
Is he gonna live?
我想这得看我们的了。
Be up to us, i suppose.
太远太迟了，找不到医生。
Too far and too late to fetch the doc.
好吧，我可以去。如果有必要，我可以骑一整夜。
Well, i can go. ride all night if i have to.
我相信你会的。
I'm sure you would.
所以呢?
So?
你就待在这里。把那个女巫交出来，黑兹尔。
You'll stay right here. hand over that witch hazel.
那是违法的。
That is an outlaw.
在逃亡中，他把马射了下来。
On the run, shot off his horse.
你觉得他杀了人?
You think he killed somebody?
怀亚特，我知道的和你一样多。
Wyatt, i know just as much as you do.
那是什么?
What's that for?
把伤口封紧，免得他一夜之间失血过多而死。
Seal the wound tight so he don't bleed out overnight.
不!胸部受伤时千万不要抬脚。
No! don't never elevate the feet with a chest wound.
我见过你身上的伤疤。
I've seen the scars on your body.
因为我不会瞒着你。
'cause i ain't hid 'em from you.
现在也许你会理解你的成长。
Now maybe you'll understand your raisin'.
把你的手放在这里。
Put your hand right here.
你会在哪里?
Where you goin'?
在我回来之前继续施压。
Just keep applyin' pressure till i get back.
现在该做什么?
What now?
子弹一定会出来的。他也不会来的。
Bullet's gotta come out. and he won't make the ride.
一半的绳子。
Half that rope.
我去叫医生来。
I'll fetch the doc.
你留在这里看着他。
You'll stay here and keep an eye on him.
你真的认为有必要吗?
You really think that's necessary?
没有必要。
It ain't not necessary.
你给他降温吧
Now, why don't you cool his fever
而不是在每一个
Instead of vaporizin' on every
你脑子里有什么想法?
Thought that comes into your head?
很冷。
Trail's cold.
我们会得到他。
We'll get him.
那条狗能在水中追踪到鱼。
That dog could track a fish through water.
来吧。
Come on.
他应该醒过来，你要保持距离。
He should come to, you keep your distance.
没关系，他被绑住了。
It don't matter he's tied up.
我能应付自己。
I can handle myself.
你就照我说的做。我会尽快回来的。
You just do as i say. i'll be back soon as i can.
来吧。
Come on.
比利在哪里?
Where's billy at?
低着头。你会没事的
keep your head down. you'll be all right.
哇。
Whoa.
他在这里。
He was here.
我看不像。
Don't look like it to me.
如果我是对的，他不是一个人。
If i'm right, he weren't alone.
不管是谁，都知道他在做什么。
Whoever it is knows what he's doin'.
和我见过的所有人一样，把他的踪迹掩盖得很好。
Covered his tracks as good as anyone i've run across.
要不是下了这场雨，我早就找到他了。
Weren't for this rain, i'd have found him sooner.
我不需要你对内部运作侃侃而谈
I don't need you to speechify the inner workings
在你那愚蠢的狗脑里。
In your halfwit canine mind.
我要知道他要去哪里。
I need to know where he's headed.
那也不能缩小范围啊。
Well, that don't exactly narrow it down.
我在哪儿?
Where am i?
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
我爸爸找到了你，你快死了。
M-my pa found you, close to dead.
他把你带回来了。
He brought you back here.
噢,是吗?
Oh, yeah?
你爸是谁?
Who's your pa?
没有人。嗯…
Nobody. uh...
亨利。就一农民。
Henry. just a-a farmer.
怎么，这里只有你和他吗?
What, it's only you and him here?
他现在在这里吗?
He here now?
他就在外面。
He's just out back.
在照顾猪。
Tendin' to the hogs.
噢,是吗?
Oh, yeah?
好吧，去找他。
Well, go fetch him.
退出mov……移动!
Quit mov... moving!
现在，我不想伤害你。
Right now, i don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤害你。停止运动!
I don't want to hurt you. stop moving!
你把我的枪和背包放哪了?听我说!
Where'd you put my gun and my satchel? listen to me!
我不知道你在说什么，先生。
I don't know what you're talkin' about, mister.
别对我撒谎!
Don't you lie to me!
你对我的枪和背包做了什么?
What'd you do with my gun and my satchel?
爸爸!
Pa!
他是怎么逃脱的?
How'd he get loose?
H-he挣脱。
H-he wriggled free.
挣脱?
Wriggled free?
拿起我放在床头柜上的小刀。
And got hold of my knife i left on the bedstand.
那是我们俩的责任。
Well, that's on the both of us.
帮我把这狗娘养的绑起来。
Help me tie the son of a bitch back up.
好吧。
Okay.
你最好好好想想你给自己惹了什么麻烦。
You better think long and hard on what you got yourself into.
真有趣，我也正想告诉你呢。
Funny, i was about to tell you the same thing.
你想用它做什么?
What you aimin' to do with that?
把子弹从你身体里挖出来，
Gonna dig that bullet out of you,
也许能在这个过程中找到答案。
Maybe get some answers in the process.
我喜欢我听到的
I like what i hear,
我可能会给你点东西减轻你的痛苦。
I might be inclined to give you something to ease the pain.
不。
No.
不!
No!
好吧!听着,听着!
Okay! listen, listen!
不!
No!
从你告诉我你是谁开始。
Let's start with you tellin' me who you are.
我是法律!我是个该死的执法官!
I'm law! i'm a goddamn lawman!
他不是执法官，爸，他想杀了我。
He ain't no lawman, pa, he was fixin' to kill me.
想喝点威士忌吗?
Ready for some whisky?
我只是告诉你…我的法律。
I just told you... i'm law.
问问他关于钱的事。
Ask him about the money.
什么钱?
What money?
他问我这件事。
He asked me about it.
听。听我的。
Listen. listen to me.
好的,听着。
Okay, listen.
一个开枪的执法官带着一大包现金干什么?
What's a shot lawman doin' with a satchel full of cash?
听!
Listen!
听!如果你有脑子的话，
Listen! if you got a brain in your head,
你得让你自己和你儿子
You need to get yourself and your boy
尽快离开这里。
Out of here fast as you can.
你听到我吗?
You hear me?
不。
No.
哦,不!不,不!
Oh, no! no, no!
至少我们知道你不会死
At least we know you won't die
在我弄清楚我想知道的事情之前。
'fore i find out what i want to know.
哦,上帝。
Oh god.
再来一点。
Let me have a little more.
让我……
Let me...
骑手。
Riders.
快点，给我松绑。快点，给我松绑。
Come on, cut me loose. come on, cut me loose.
听着，他们会有三个人。
Listen, they gon' be three of 'em.
一个墨西哥。
One's a mexican.
另一个是丑狗娘养的
The other's an ugly son of a bitch
留着浓密的胡子。
With a thick beard.
和他们的领袖……
And their leader...
他们的领导人看起来是一个你不会想惹的人。
Their leader looks like a man you don't want to mess with.
相信我，你不会的。
And believe me, you don't.
不要靠近窗户。
Keep back from the window.
如果你想活命，就得放了我
If you want to live, you gotta turn me loose
把枪给我，听到了吗?
And give me my gun, hear?
他是骗子的。
He's lyin'.
我说了退后。
I said keep back.
继续。
Go on.
我能帮你吗?
Can i help you?
我是治安官山姆·凯彻姆。
I'm sheriff sam ketchum.
这些是我的副手。
These here are my deputies.
我们一直在寻找一个在逃的人。
We've been scoutin' for a man on the run.
最近被称为咖喱。
Lately goes by the name of curry.
被枪杀了。
Been shot.
六英尺高，棕色头发，据说很英俊，
Six foot, brown hair, said to be handsome,
尽管大多数人想要他的功劳
Though most would want him credited
只为了邪恶。
For nothing but devilry.
我只知道，他很危险。
What i do know is, he's dangerous.
你在这附近见过符合描述的人吗?
You seen anybody around here answers that description?
说你是治安官?我怎么都认不出你了?
Say you're a sheriff? how's it i don't recognize you?
我们是从很远的伍兹郡来的。
We're from way over in woods county.
现在，我们要找的咖喱
Now, this curry we're looking for,
他手上有搜查令
He's got a warrant on him there
在密苏里和田纳西
In missouri and tennessee.
可能还会声称他就是法律。
Might also claim he's the law.
他有过这样的欺骗史。
He's got a history of such chicanery.
远非如此。他是一个杀手。
Far from it. he's a killer.
他还会再杀人。
He will kill again.
你不打算开枪
You're not fixin' to shoot
我们中有谁有枪，是吗?
Any of us with that pistol, are you?
到目前为止我还没理由。
So far i got no reason to.
这是个好消息。
That's good news.
在你把那东西举起来之前，你得好好想想，农夫。
You'll want to think 'fore you raise that thing up, farmer.
没什么好担心的，朋友。
Nothing to be worried about here, friend.
只是我在做的一个小项目，仅此而已。
Just a little project i'm working on, that's all.
有多少人住在这里?
How many people live out here?
这和你有什么区别?
What difference is that to you?
我只是想确保你的安全。
I'm trying to make sure you're safe, is all.
不关你的事
Wouldn't seem to be your business,
鉴于你是伍兹郡来的。
Seeing as how you're from woods county.
你结婚了吗?
You married?
看到那边有个坟墓。
Saw a grave over there.
我的妻子。
My wife.
十年前死于肺结核
Died ten years back from tuberculosis.
我的慰问。
My condolences.
这太可怕了。
Horrible way to go.
告诉他们,爸爸。告诉他们!
Tell 'em, pa. tell 'em!
马克卡迪，玛丽·霍布斯·马克卡迪。
Marie hobbs mccarty, the marker said.
你姓麦卡蒂?
Your last name mccarty?
这是正确的。
That's right.
名字吗?
First name?
亨利。
Henry.
我猜霍布斯是她的人。
So hobbs was her people, i'm guessing.
因为我注意到在东边有个霍布斯农场。
'cause i noticed a hobbs ranch to the east of here.
她的兄弟。
Her brothers.
啊哈。
Uh-huh.
从目前的情况来看
Well, from the looks of things,
你在外面待了好多年了。
You've been out here a good many years.
好的情况。
Nice situation.
都在山上安家。
All nestled up here in the hills.
从远处很难看到。
Hard to see from a distance.
这些和你要找的人有什么关系?
What's any of this got to do with the man you're lookin' for?
没什么，我承认。
Not much, i'll grant you.
很久以前，呃…
Long time ago, uh...
有个家伙在新墨西哥的亚利桑那州惹了些麻烦。
Was a fella caused some trouble down arizona, new mexico way.
听说他叫麦卡蒂。
Heard he went by the name mccarty.
我想知道他是不是你的亲戚。
I was wondering if he might be your kin.
你抓错猪耳朵了。
You got the wrong pig by the ear.
的意思吗?
Meaning?
除了这里，我哪儿都不认识麦卡锡，
I don't know no mccartys anywhere but here,
我所有的亲人都去世了。
And all my kin is deceased.
现在我要做家务了
Now i got chores to tend to
没有足够的木材来做晚饭。
And scant wood to cook my supper.
我没见过你要找的人。
I ain't seen the man you're after.
我会留意的。
I'll keep my eyes peeled.
一定要通知治安官
Be sure to alert the good sheriff
在切克沙镇
In chickasha if i should run across him.
嗯,然后。
Well, then.
谢谢你的帮助。
I thank you for your help.
看来又是一条死胡同了，伙计们。
Looks like another dead end, boys.
今晚你们一定要锁门。
You be sure to lock your doors tonight.
保持安全。
Stay safe.
来吧。
Come on.
现在你想留着这个了吗?
Now you're inclined to hang onto that?
我想你可能需要帮助。
I thought you might be needin' help.
你想告诉我这是怎么被炒掉的吗?
You wanna tell me how this got fired?
诚实,pa。
Honest, pa.
别对我撒谎!
Don't you lie to me!
我想知道那是什么感觉。
I wanted to know what it's like.
我是50英里内唯一没开过枪的人。
I am the only boy for 50 miles that's never fired one.
你甚至不让我碰你的旧猎枪。
You won't even let me lay hand on your old shotgun.
如果你教不了我，那我就自己来吧。
So if you can't teach me proper, i gotta do it myself.
你再敢碰我的东西，我就打烂你!
You get into my things again, i will crack your crust!
你是个愚蠢无用的老头。
You're a stupid, worthless old man.
一生，却一无所得
A whole life, and nothin' to show for it
但是这个破旧的老农场
But this rundown old farm
还有一个会让你孤独终老的男孩
And a boy who's gonna leave you alone to die
只要他有能力。
As soon as he's able.
让我猜一猜。
Let me guess.
你要告诉我他不是
You gon' tell me that he ain't
你是伍兹县的治安官。
The sheriff of woods county, you are.
他们不是执法者，他们是银行劫匪。
They ain't lawmen, they're bank robbers.
不管怎样，他们还剩下什么。
Well, what's left of them, anyway.
撞翻了亚当斯快车。
Knocked over the adams express.
我和我的副手追了上去，杀了两个
Me and my deputies gave chase, killed two of 'em,
包括拿着赃物的那个。
Including the one carrying the loot.
银行劫匪戴着徽章?
Bank robbers wearin' badges?
他们带走了我和我的人。
That they took off me and my men.
他才是那个冒充法律的人。
He's the one impersonating the law.
但你带着钱跑了。
But you made off with the money.
是啊，我抓住了。
Hell, yeah, i grabbed it.
那你为什么不把它带回伍兹郡?
Then why ain't you back with it in woods county?
哦，我不知道。为什么会这样?
Oh, i don't know. why does it look like?
我的首要任务是
And my first priority was
活着离开那群人。
Getting away from that bunch alive.
所以我拼命地骑，直到骑不动为止。
That's why i rode like hell till i couldn't no more.
我记得的最后一件事
There's the last thing i remembered,
直到我在这里醒来
Till i woke up here.
我知道我在说什么
Look, i know what i'm saying
听起来很荒谬。
Sounds ridiculous to you and all.
它确实是这样。
That it does.
他们为什么不开枪打死你
Why they didn't shoot you dead
我不知道。
On the spot just now, i don't know.
但我可以向你保证…
But i can guarantee you...
他们会回来的。
They'll be back.
只有一件事我想不明白
Only thing i can't figure
为什么是那个老人
Is why the old man
愿意为一个陌生人冒生命危险。
Would risk his neck for a stranger.
也许有人给了他一部分钱。
Maybe he got offered a cut of the money.
直觉告诉我不是这样的。
Something tells me that ain't it.
我们任何人都可以干掉他。
Any one of us could have taken him out.
我们现在就该这么做。
Which is what we should do now.
-骑上去，完成它。-还没呢。
- ride up, finish it. - not just yet.
就因为一个摇摇晃晃的老农民?
'cause of some shaky old farmer?
他拿枪的姿势和我见过的农民都不一样。
He didn't hold that pistol like any farmer i've ever seen.
我们有三个人。
There are three of us.
我们没有在银行里跑，也没有登上舞台
We don't run up in a bank, or ride up on a stage
不知道里面有谁
Without knowing who's in it.
我们知道里面有咖喱。用我们的钱!
We know curry's in there. with our money!
所以你才要去侦察
Which is why you're going to reconnoiter
那个所谓的农家
That so-called farmer's place
确保咖喱不会跑掉。
And make sure curry don't skedaddle.
很乐意。
Gladly.
在我们到达之前，不要轻举妄动。
Don't make a move till we get there.
很好。
Fine.
——达根。-我说好吧。
- duggan. - i said fine.
日出时，你和我去切克沙镇
Come sunup, you and me will head into chickasha,
雇佣一些枪支。
Hire some guns.
理解。
Understood.
在路上，我们将拜访农夫霍布斯…
On the way, we'll pay a call on farmer hobbs...
看看他有没有什么有趣的消息
Find out if he's got anything interesting
告诉我们关于亨利·麦卡蒂的事
To tell us about ol' henry mccarty.
怀亚特。进来吧。
Wyatt. come on in.
-我快好了。-留到明天早上吧。
- i'm almost finished. - leave it till morning.
来吧。
Come on.
要是我能自己吃就好了。
It'd be a damn sight easier if i could feed myself.
干脆不给你吃就好了。
Be a damn sight easier not to feed you at all.
-你和我见过吗?-我会记得的。
- you and me ever met? - that i'd remember.
你当警长多久了?
How long you been a sheriff?
-我想是18年了。-你是怎么开始的?
- i'd say onto 18 years now. - how'd you get your start?
我是大比尔·汤普森的副手
I was a deputy for big bill thompson
在巴克斯特弹簧。
In baxter springs.
巴克斯特弹簧。巴克斯特温泉,密苏里州吗?
Baxter springs. baxter springs, missouri?
——堪萨斯州。-瘦子，大耳朵?
- kansas. - skinny fella, big ears?
体格魁伟的。
Heavyset.
左耳缺了一部分
Missing part of his left ear from
一个喝醉的矿工朝他开枪。
A drunk miner taking a potshot at him.
-我听说是一个喝醉的妓女。-是吗?
- i heard it was a drunk whore. - oh, you did?
你住在巴克斯特泉的哪个地方?
Which part of baxter springs you live in?
一个公寓。在格兰特车站附近。
A boarding house. out near grant's stage station.
房东太太叫什么名字?
What was the landlady's name?
她不是什么淑女。
She weren't no lady.
她是个叫汉娜的讨厌的老混蛋。
She a nasty ol' cuss named hannah.
你遇到过乔治骗子吗?
You ever run into a george crook?
你是说乔治将军?
You mean general george?
Sumbitch奉献了他的一生
Sumbitch dedicated his life
把怪兽赶出领地。
To driving the caddo out of the territory.
你怎么会在巴克斯特泉?
How in the hell did you end up in baxter springs?
就像其他傻瓜一样
Well, like every other fool
梦想着轻松致富，挖锡。
Dreaming of easy riches and digging for tin.
直到我意识到根本没有。
Till i realized there weren't none.
只是一堆关于矿井的鬼故事
Just a bunch of ghost stories about a mine
靠近斯莫基山河。
Near smokey hill river.
然后我…我破产了。工作很难得到。
Then i... i was broke. work was hard to come by.
幸运的是，大比尔喜欢上了我。
I'm lucky big bill took a liking to me.
否则我…我不知道我会怎么样。
Otherwise i... i don't know what would have come of me.
我…很抱歉我之前袭击了你儿子。
I... i'm sorry i jumped your boy before.
我在一个陌生的地方醒来，不知道他是谁……
I woke up in a strange place, didn't know who he was...
我被关在某个藏身处当人质。
I was being held hostage in some hideout.
你觉得这里像是藏身处吗?
This look like a hideout to you?
我无意中听到他早些时候说的话。
I overheard what he said earlier.
他不是那个意思。
He didn't mean any of that.
是的,他做到了。
Yes, he did.
我给你一只手。别逼我把它摘下来。
I'll give you one hand free. don't make me take it off.
好吧。
All right.
你爸爸是种地吗?
Was farming what your daddy did?
我父亲在我三岁的时候去世了，在堪萨斯。
My daddy died when i was 3, up in kansas.
除了种地以外，他几乎什么都做。
And he did near everything but work the land.
我15岁就成了孤儿。
I was orphaned at 15.
比我认识我父母的时间长了13年。
That's 13 years longer than i knew my folks.
啊。你在哪长大的?
Ah. whereabouts you grow up?
新墨西哥州。
New mexico.
——这部分?-萨姆纳堡。
- which part? - fort sumner.
出生和长大。你听说过吗?
Born and raised. you heard of it?
比利被枪杀的地方，对吧?
Where billy the kid was shot, wasn't it?
人们知道它的主要原因。
Main reason anyone know it.
事发当晚我就在现场。
I was there the night it happened.
这是怎么回事?
How's that?
我当时只是个孩子。
I was just a boy.
我以前能挣多少钱就挣多少钱
I used to make what money i could
帮一个叫彼得·麦克斯韦的人做家务。
Doing chores for a fella by the name of peter maxwell.
那个送孩子过夜的彼得·麦克斯韦尔。
Same peter maxwell put the kid up for the night.
彼得·麦克斯韦向加勒特告密
Same peter maxwell tipped off garrett
他的副手，poe和mckinney
And his deputies, poe and mckinney,
那孩子被关在那里。
The kid was holed up there.
我在扫货摊。
I was sweeping the stalls.
当我看到加勒特走进屋子我…
When i saw garrett walk in the house, i...
我觉得这没什么。
I don't think nothing of it.
但是比利不在里面。不,无论如何。
But billy wasn't in there. not then, leastways.
-知道我是怎么知道的吗?——如何?
- know how i know? - how?
他光着脚，只穿着小腿袖子，
He was barefoot in his shin sleeves,
从鹿的尸体上切肉
Cutting the meat off a deer carcass
离我工作的地方不到20英尺
Not 20 feet from where i was working.
我看到他从谷仓门往外偷看，
I saw him peer through the barn door,
他看到坡和麦金尼站在门廊上。
And he saw poe and mckinney on the porch there.
他停止雕刻，死死地盯着我的眼睛。
He stopped carving, looked me dead in my eye.
他说:“低头，你会没事的。”
He said, "keep your head down, you'll be all right."
比利直接去了麦克斯韦的房间，
So billy went straight to maxwell's room,
很快发现里面不止是麦克斯韦。
Realized pretty quick it ain't just maxwell in there.
他喊道:“¿quien es?”还有谁es ?"
He called out, "¿quien es? ¿quien es?"
因为比利的西班牙语说得跟墨西哥人一样好。
'cause billy spoke spanish as good as a mexican.
帕特的答案?
Pat's answer?
两个镜头。一个打得很宽，另一个打在胸口。
Two shots. one wide of the mark, and the other one in the chest.
比利这孩子就这样完了。
That was the end of billy the kid.
你看到了这一切。
And you seen it all.
我肯定是这样做的。
I most certainly did.
看到那孩子的尸体也被拖走了，
Saw the kid's body get hauled off too,
裹在血淋淋的床单里。
Wrapped in a bloody sheet.
足以让我明白这不是适合我的生活。
Enough to teach me that ain't no life for me.
我宁愿停止这场疯狂也不愿参与其中。
I'd rather stop this crazy than be part of it anyway.
嗯…
Well...
该死的。
Damn.
如果我知道，只需要一个好故事
If i knew all it took was a good story
让你给我松绑
For you to cut me loose.
你在马鞍上还能站直吗?
You well enough to stay upright in the saddle?
——不是很难。-我要你离开这里。
- not hardly. - i want you out of here.
我想等到天亮也不行吧?
I suppose waiting till sunup ain't an option?
如果我一个人在这里，情况就不一样了。
If i was alone out here, it'd be different.
好吧，我想我准备好了。
Well, then, i guess i'm ready.
好。
Good.
把它。
Take it.
我去拿你的战利品。
I'll fetch your loot.
——爸爸?-怀亚特!下来!
- pa? - wyatt! get down!
我想我没事了。
I-i think i'm all right.
是……他了吗?
Is... is he hit?
他刚刚昏过去了。给我。
He just passed out. give me that.
我比你想的更擅长。
I'm better with it than you think.
等我教你该怎么做。
Not until i teach you proper.
-我自学了-嘘
- i've taught myself - shush.
你去哪了?
Now, where'd you get to?
-他在房子下面。——嘘。
- he's under the house. - shh.
我希望你做得够好。
I hope you got good enough with this.
上帝不允许这种事发生，但射杀一个人
God forbid it happens, but shooting a man
和击中目标是不同的…
Is different than hitting a target...
一条你无法跨越的线。
A line you can't cross back over.
我知道。
I know that.
除非你做了，否则你是做不到的。
You couldn't until you've done it.
如果他进来……
If he comes in here...
你扣动扳机。
You pull that trigger.
瞄准胸部。
Aim for the chest.
一直开枪，直到打中为止。
And keep firing until you hit it.
你要去哪里?
Where you going?
婊子养的!
Son of a bitch!
混蛋!
Cocksucker!
他妈的。
Fuck.
大便。
Shit.
其他人在哪里?他们关闭吗?
Where's the others? they close?
去地狱。
Go to hell.
我来这里太多次了
I've been here too often to let
像你这样有才干的人检查了我的行李。
A man of your caliber overhaul my baggage.
回答我，否则你就死定了。
Answer me, or it ends for you right now.
去死吧，你这个混蛋。
Go to hell, you bastard.
他想把我们俩都杀了。
He was fixin' to kill us both.
我看到了。
I saw.
可能是来这里看的，然后贪得无厌。
Probably here to watch and got greedy.
其他人会来的。
The others will be coming.
首先，我们得处理掉这具尸体。
First thing, we gotta get rid of this body.
我们要怎么做?
How we gonna do that?
我们不是。
We ain't.
我知道这感觉不像。
I know it don't feel like it.
你很幸运，它只是擦伤了你。
You're lucky it just grazed ya.
如果你知道我找到了那把枪，
If you know i found that gun,
你知道我看到衣柜后面有什么了。
You know i saw what's in the back of that closet.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我就是我。
I'm who i am.
你不是一直在宣扬要诚实吗?
Aren't you always preaching about being honest?
真相会让你自由吗?
The truth will set you free?
我从来没有对你撒过谎。
I've never lied to you.
不是没告诉我真相
Isn't not telling me the whole story
同样的事?
The same damn thing?
我做了一些我希望能收回的事。
I've done things i wish i could take back.
在你之前很久。之前你的马。
A long time before you. before your ma.
你不该听的事。
Things that you got no business hearing.
你都不尊重我，我怎么能尊重你?
How am i supposed to respect you if you ain't respecting me?
我尊重你。
I am respecting you.
如果你不明白，
And if you don't understand that,
我刚才说的话你一个字都没听见。
You ain't heard a word i just said.
不，我听到了。我一点也不相信。
No, i heard it. i just don't believe a bit of it.
保持你的头低着
keep your head down.
低下头。你会没事的。
Keep your head down. you'll be all right.
你会没事的。
you'll be all right.
哇。
Whoa.
-早上好-早上好。
- morning - morning.
-有什么我能帮忙的吗?-我当然希望如此。
- something i can help you with? - i sure hope so.
你这地方真不错。和平的。安静。
Nice place you got here. peaceful. quiet.
鸟打猎。
Bird hunting.
没有什么比这更好的了。
Nothing quite like the flush of the bevy.
你一定很厉害。
You must be quite the shot.
尽我所能。
Do what i can.
我羡慕你。
I envy you.
我不能出去打猎
I don't get to go out hunting
尽管我现在很想这么做
As much as i'd like to these days.
有什么能帮你的吗，先生?
Something i can help you with, mister?
我爸爸过去常打野鸡。
My daddy used to hunt pheasant.
我的工作就是把它们清理干净。
It was always my damn job to clean 'em.
切开胸部的皮肤，把它剥掉。
Oh, cutting the skin on the breast, peeling it back.
但久而久之，我发现最好的办法
But over time, i figured the best way
为了去除内脏…
To get rid of their innards...
就是劈开鸟的背用那种方式接近他们。
Was to split the bird's back. get to 'em that way.
这就是你的发现吗?
Is that what you find?
看,我不…
Look, i don't...
我想成为联合国的邻居，但是…
Mean to be un-neighborly, but...
但是说重点?确定。
But get to the point? sure.
我想问你几个问题，关于，
I wanted to ask you a couple questions about, uh,
你的妹夫。
Your brother-in-law.
他跟你有什么关系?
Well, what concern is he of yours?
这正是我想弄明白的。
That's what i'm trying to figure out.
我有个疯狂的想法…
You see, i got this crazy idea...
也许麦克卡迪还有更多
There might be more to ol' mccarty
一眼就能看出来。
Than meets the eye.
你是什么执法官之类的吗?
You supposed be some kind of lawman or something?
就像这样。
Something like that.
我觉得你该走了。
Well, i think it's time you left.
我们是来找答案的。
Well, we came here for some answers.
不抓到他们，我们不走。
We ain't leaving till i get 'em.
这样吗?
That so?
我应该……
I should...
现在我们要怎么把他抬起来?
Now how the hell we gonna pick his ass up?
好吧。好的,谢谢你。
Okay. okay, thank you.
哦,上帝。好吧。
Oh, god. okay.
我不适合旅行。我不是。
I'm no good to travel. i'm not.
你带着孩子离开这里。
You take the boy, you get out of here.
凯彻姆和他的人到达时，
When ketchum and his men arrive,
我会尽量拖住他们。
I'll hold them off as long as i can.
-去他的!-怀亚特。
- the hell with that! - wyatt.
我们有枪。
We got guns.
你已经赤手空拳杀了一个了。
You already killed one of them barehanded.
填满一个包。我们离开。
Fill a pack. we're leaving.
我警告你。
I'm warning you.
他回来了。
He's back.
离开休息。
Leave the rest.
我们不能让他在这里等死。
We can't just leave him here to die.
我绝对不会失去你的
I am damn sure not gonna lose you
和我们无关的事。
Over something that ain't our fight.
你爸是对的。
Your pa's right.
我已经长大了，可以自己做决定了，
I am old enough to make my own decisions,
不管你是否准备好接受这个事实。
Whether you are ready to accept that or not.
是的。这是我来完成的。
Yeah. this is mine to finish.
继续,现在。我会没事的。
Go on, now. i'll be all right.
哇。
Whoa.
咖喱!有人在家吗?
Curry! anybody home?
你们需要什么吗?
You gentlemen need something?
我们是来抓逃犯的。
We're here for our fugitive.
我昨天告诉过你我没见过他。
I told you yesterday i ain't seen him.
我的直觉告诉我那不是真的。
My intuition tells me that's not true.
我就直说了…
I'll make it easy...
你把他交出来，我们就放了你和那孩子。
You hand him over, we let you and the boy go free.
另一个选择是，我们带走他。
The other option is, we take him.
然后你和那孩子就会死。
And you and the boy die.
你接受这个条件。
You take that deal.
这是我自愿的，你不是。
I signed up for this, you didn't.
看，你的马已经备好了。
See your horses are already saddled.
你可以走了。
You can just ride on out of here.
你我都知道我们会死的
You and i both know we'll be dead
在我们上马之前。
Before we mount our horses.
如果这变成了某种brigasee
'fore this turns into some kinda brigasee,
不如我们来解决这个问题，
Why don't me and you settle this,
关节和头骨。
Knuckle and skull.
作为一个农民，你经历了很多争斗。
You got a lot of fight for a farmer.
事情不是这样的。
That ain't the way this plays out.
带给他!
Bring him up!
艾尔?
Al?
听我的。会发生什么
Listen to me. what's gonna happen
将很快发生。
Will happen quick.
我会尽量拖延，但我希望你从后面溜出去
I'll stall long as i can, but i want you to sneak out back
躲在罗杰的磨坊里
And hole up at roger's mill...
在那里等我。
And wait for me there.
只有在必要时才使用这个。
Only use this if you have to.
-让我来打。-我做不好
- let me fight. - i can't do this right
如果我担心保护你
If i'm worried about protecting you.
把我翻过来。
Just turn me over.
你不去，他们会把我们都杀了。
You don't, they're gonna kill us all.
你我都知道
You and me both know
反正他们也要这么做。
They're fixin' to do that anyway.
你还想让我跑出去面对枪林弹雨?
And yet you expect me to run out into sure gunfire?
你儿子是对的。
Your boy's right.
呆在室内。
Stay inside.
离窗户远点。
Stay away from the window.
你必须射击，瞄准胸部，然后…
You have to shoot, aim for the chest, and...
继续开枪，直到我打中什么。
Keep firing till i hit something.
我有些怀疑
I've had some suspicions
你是谁，亨利·麦卡蒂
About who you are, henry mccarty.
我得承认，这名字就像刺一样刺进了我的心。
I got to admit, that name sticks in me like a thorn.
我的好奇心被激起了。
My curiosity was aroused.
我希望艾尔能给我点启示。
I was hoping al here might shed some light.
他什么都不会说。
He wouldn't say shit.
即使在我的孩子们…
Even after my boys were...
这个词是什么?在他们的问题中强调。
What's the word? uh, emphatic in their question.
你可能认为我不是治安官。
You probably concluded i'm no sheriff.
这些人也不是我的副手。
Nor are these men my deputies.
我们中没有一个人花时间
Not a one of us had spent time
一个月前在伍兹郡。
In woods county before a month ago.
你呢?
What about you?
你从哪里来?
Where'd you come from?
除了这里，地球上的每一个地方。
Every place on earth but this.
所以要它。
So be it.
最后的报价。
Last offer.
这个张口结舌的混蛋
This tongue-tied piece of shit
为了警长咖喱和钱。
For sheriff curry in there and the money.
你得到了你想要的。
You get what you want.
我得到了我想要的。
I get what i want.
我们各走各的路，不流血。
We go our separate ways without blood spilled.
不是你的，也不是我的。
Not yours, not mine.
不是你那个监视我的孩子
Not that boy of yours i see surveilling
所有这些都通过那扇窗户。
All this through that window.
如果我想要流血
If i wanted bloodshed,
我很久以前就会冲进去开枪了。
I'd have busted in there guns a-blazin' a long time ago.
我相信你知道的。
I believe you know that.
你把我姐夫留在原地。
You leave my brother-in-law right where he is.
滚出我的地盘。
Turn and ride your asses off my property.
你这么做，我就饶你一命。
You do that, and i'll let you live.
听到了吗，伙计们?
You hear that, fellas?
这是一个温和的乡巴佬说的吗?
Is that the talk of a mild old sodbuster?
我认为不是。
I think not.
不。
Nah.
这听起来完全是另一回事。
That sounds like something else altogether.
霍布斯!
Hobbs!
你能告诉我任何可能改变局面的事吗?
Anything you could tell me might change the equation here?
去你的，你个长篇大论的混蛋。
Kiss my ass, you long-winded son of a bitch.
你有一双，我承认。
You got a pair, i'll give you that.
最后机会。
Last chance, al.
你不知道你要释放的地狱风暴。
You have no idea the hell storm you fixin' to let loose.
我已经被警告过了。
Consider me properly warned.
一件容易的事。哇。
Easy. whoa.
容易,伙计。
Easy, fella.
该死的。
Goddamn.
看看这个。
Look at that.
我想说她玩完了。
I'd say she's done.
这难道不是一件美好的事情吗?
Ain't that a thing of beauty?
怀亚特!
Wyatt!
进入!
Get in!
你还在吗?
You still with us?
我的少。
Less of me.
哇。哇。
Whoa. whoa.
马克卡迪!
Mccarty!
你死了吗?
You dead yet?
我当然不是。
I sure ain't.
我假设我没见过
I'm assuming the fact i ain't seen
今天早上我的朋友达根
My man duggan this morning
说明他肯定和你有过交集，
Means he must have crossed paths with you,
事情并没有如他所愿。
And things didn't go his way.
鉴于我刚刚杀了你的人，
Seeing as how i just killed your man al here,
我想说这对我们来说是正确的。
I'd say that squares us.
没有更多的游戏。
No more games.
给你一分钟时间出来。
You got one minute to come out.
你差点害死我们俩
You nearly got us both killed,
是关于你的眼泪和愤怒吗
Which is about all your tears and rage
相当于。
Would have amounted to.
现在把头低下。你会没事的。
Now keep your damn head down. you'll be all right.
保持你的头低，
keep your head down,
你会没事的
you'll be all right.
坡和麦金尼站在门廊上。
Poe and mckinney were on the porch.
加勒特进了房子
Garrett went in the house.
两枪……但他……
Two shots... but he...
你跟他们说西班牙语。
And you were speaking spanish to 'em.
但他没杀你。
But he didn't kill you.
他帮你逃跑了。
He helped you escape.
你是他。
You're him.
他是谁?
He's who?
邦尼。
Bonney.
爸，他在说什么?
Pa, what is he talking about?
爸爸!
Pa!
聪明的选择,朋友。
Smart choice, friend.
他说了什么?
What's he saying?
你敢走出去。
Don't you dare step outside.
啊。
Ah.
啊!
Aah!
他妈的。
Fuck.
你对吧?
You all right?
哦。
Oh.
怀亚特。去拿一桶水和一些破布来。
Wyatt. fetch a pail of water and some rags.
继续。
Go on.
你肯定有过好日子。
You've certainly seen better days.
我就知道你很面熟。
I knew you had a familiar face.
一开始我就是想不起来是什么。
I just couldn't place it at first.
我们去找医生。
We'll get the doc.
首先我得减缓出血。
First i gotta slow the bleed.
这么多年来你是怎么藏起来的?
How you manage to stay hidden all these years?
把你的衣服脱下来。
Let's get some of this shirt off you.
我可以用它绑住这条腿。
I can use it to tie off this leg.
哦,狗屎。
Well, shit.
我真希望你没看到。
I wish you didn't see that.
就像我之前听到你告诉你儿子的一样。
It's just like i heard you tell your boy before.
我不是撒谎了吗，我只是没告诉你全部真相。
Ain't that i lied, i just never told you the whole truth.
你是法律吗?
Was you law at all?
伍兹县治安官，就像我说的。
Sheriff of woods county, just like i said.
我和我的副手们
Me and my deputies,
我们在春天就和凯彻姆签约了。
We signed on with ketchum back in the spring.
我们必须占领他们的品牌。
We had to take their brand.
跟他们干过几次。
Done a few jobs with 'em.
但我们发现他们在计划
But we figured out they was planning
在最后一次行动时干掉我们。
To gun us down on this last go.
所以我们想抢在他们前面。
So we tried to beat 'em to the punch.
跑掉了，他们从远处把我插了进去。
Took off, and they plugged me from a distance.
他们会追杀我到天涯海角。
They'd have hunted me to the end of the earth.
很抱歉我来了这里。
I'm sorry i ended up here.
我最不想让你知道的就是真相。
Last thing i wanted, you wanna know the truth of it.
因为你那时对我很好。
'cause you were good to me back then.
嗯。
Huh.
我永远不能容忍你做了他们说的那些事。
I could never square you done the things they said.
虽然我现在相信了。
Though i sure as hell can believe it now.
我都不记得你了。
I don't even remember you.
你为什么要这么做?我只是个农场工人。
Well, why would you? i was just a ranch hand.
现在是我杀了比利这个孩子。
Now i get to be the man who killed billy the kid.
-你坚持住，我去叫医生。——没有。
- you hold on, i'll get the doc. - no.
Pa。
Pa.
我能走到这一步真是奇迹。
It's a miracle i made it this far.
一旦这件事传出去…
Once this gets out...
你会听到一些关于我的事。
You gonna hear some things about me.
有些是真的。
Some of it's true.
很多都不是。
A lot of it ain't.
事实是……
Fact is...
我都不知道我以前是谁了。
I don't even know who or what i was anymore.
我不相信救赎。
I don't believe in redemption.
但男人可以找到某种慰藉…
But a man can find some kind of solace...
如果他有像你这样的儿子要抚养。
If he's got a boy like you to raise.
世界在变化。
The world is changing.
你去看吧。
You go see it.
我再也不属于那个地方了。
It's a place i don't belong in no more.
我希望……
I'm hoping...
你做的事情。
You do.
爸爸?
Pa?
来吧。
Come on.